Antonio Martínez

antonio@ramada.ml +506 6017 0413 San Jose, Costa Rica www.antoniomartz.ml,

Senior Web Developer

Summary

7 years of professional career as a web developer.

Good understanding of PHP and modern JavaScript (ES6), using OOP programming and MVC pattern design. Excellent debugging skills and good webmaster concepts (SSL, DNS, IP, Apache, Nginx, IIS, CGI).

MySQL database design, normalization, administration, and SQL optimization.

Good understanding of web services and SOA-related standards like REST / OAuth / JSON.

Clean code and strong frontend skills (HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Angular CLI, Bootstrap, jQuery).

Certifications: CompTIA, ISC, GSEC, CEH, CAP, OSCP, GCFE, SEC541.

A day in my life may consist of: Work with JavaScript promises, design a responsive landing page, develop a custom WordPress plugin, adding an API endpoint, MySQL database design or normalization, read the documentation of new PHP releases, bugs find and fix, back up websites, programming new components or services, environment setting, files compression and optimization, take some Jira ticket, deployment, and some more cool stuff.

Professional experience

Web developer

MY BOOKIE • San Jose, Costa Rica

MyBookie Sportsbook & Casino.

Advanced WordPress Development.

Web developer

Jazz Gaming Solutions • San Jose, Costa Rica

I was responsible for developing, implementing, and maintaining mostly internal sportsbooks web applications like REST APIs, Websites, and Databases. I collaborated with technical and business staff in the design, development, testing, implementation, and production support of web applications in PHP, JavaScript, Angular CLI, HTML5, CSS3, Git, and some other cool technologies.

Web developer

PROFI • San Jose, Costa Rica

At PROFI, I mostly work with WordPress.

Working with project managers and designers, I was responsible for programming custom themes, custom plugins, mega menus, dashboards, reports, forms, landing pages, import, export, and backup websites.

Web developer

01/2021 - 04/2021

01/2018 - 09/2020

04/2014 - 02/2017

At my current position, I am working on a web reporting system for casinos. Giving the maintenance and programming of new reports, new features, updates, and API integrations. We use technologies such as PHP, MySQL, jQuery, CSS, HTML, AJAX, JSON, Git. In addition to full-stack development, I also working on a lot of server-side tasks. I have helped to set up a lot of development environments and server configurations. (LAMP, WAMP).

Web developer

Netsoft • San Jose, Costa Rica

03/2013 - 02/2014

Programming and maintaining ERP systems. The principal, Dolibarr, a very robust open-source made in PHP. I was responsible for things like, develop new custom reports, migrate and export data in JSON and SQL formats, modify MySQL databases, PHP SMTP emails, templates design with HTML and CSS, API integrations.

Technologies

- PHP
- JavaScript
- JQuery
- Sass
- WordPress
- Jira
- · Gitflow

- MySQL
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- · JSON
- Apache
- HTML5
- Angular CLI

LinkedIn Skill Assessment badge

Education

High school

Liceo Ingeniero Manuel Benavides Rodriguez • San Jose, Costa Rica Currently completing courses in computer science, robotics and statistics 02/2015

Languages

English
Spanish

Some projects I have worked on:

https://mybookie.ag

https://plive.ganchrow.com

https://www.cipreporting.com

https://jazzsports.ag

https://scoresandodds.com

https://stayincostarica.com

https://tabacon.com